Saskia Nowicki

Research Associate, Environmental Systems Science for Policy
Geography and the Environment · University of Oxford · S Parks Road OX1 3QY, UK
Saskia.nowicki@ouce.ox.ac.uk +44 7464 753326 saskia-nowicki.github.io

Overview

As a social-ecological systems specialist, I do solution-focused research that cuts across natural, social, and health sciences to respond to long-standing and emerging water quality risks. I work collaboratively with interdisciplinary research teams and with partners beyond academia to co-produce insight that supports just transitions for healthy freshwater ecosystems and equitable safe water service delivery.

Employment

First class honours, distinction

Smith School of Enterprise and the Environment, University of Oxford Postdoctoral researcher Research assistant	Oxford, UK 06/2021 - present 09/2016 - 2018
School of Geography and the Environment, University of Oxford Casual lecturer Teaching assistant	Oxford, UK 09/2021 - present 09/2018 - 2021
Dept for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, Central Science Division Policy secondment, One Health governance strategy	London, UK 10/2022 - 03/2023
Dept of Earth Sciences, University of Oxford Tutor, Myanmar TIDE Programme	Oxford, UK 04/2019 - 2020
Oxford Policy Management, WASH Team Consultant	Oxford, UK 09/2016 - 01/2017
SRK Consulting, Geochemistry Team Consultant	Vancouver, Canada 06/2012 -2015
Gregory-Eaves Limnology Lab, McGill University Research assistant	Montreal, Canada 2011
Education	
University of Oxford, DPhil Water and Health	2017 - 2021

Thesis: Data, Decisions, & Drinking-Water Safety [view online]	
University of Oxford, MSc Water Science, Policy and Management Thesis: Variability in Drinking-water Microbial Contamination Risk Top of class, distinction	2015 - 2016
McGill University, BSc (Hons) Environmental Science Concentration: Water Environments and Ecosystems, Biological Stream	2008 - 2012

Research Projects

Publications

BOOKS

Pearson, E.S. and John Wishart (eds.). 1943. "Student's" Collected Papers London: Biometrika Office.

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Student. 1938. "Comparison between Balanced and Random Arrangements on Field Plots." *Biometrika* 29(3-4): 363–378.

Student. 1936. "Co-operation in Large Scale Experiments." Supplement to Journal of the Royal Statistical Society 3(2): 115–136.

Student. 1931. "On the z Test." $Biometrika\ 23(3-4)$: 407-408.

Student. 1931. "The Lanarkshire Milk Experiment." Biometrika 23(3-4): 398–406.

Student. 1929. "Statistics in Biological Research." Nature 124: 93

Student. 1927. "Errors of Routine Analysis." Biometrika 19(1-2): 151–164.

Student. 1926. "Mathematics and Agronomy." Journal of the American Society of Agronomy 18.

Student. 1925. "New Tables for Testing the Significance of Observations." Metron 5(3): 105–108.

Student. 1923. "On Testing Varieties of Cereals." Biometrika 15(3-4): 271-293.

Student. 1921. "An Experimental Determination of the Probable Error of Dr. Spearman's Correlation Co-efficient" *Biometrika* 13(2-3): 263–282.

Student. 1917. "Tables for Estimating the Probability That the Given Mean of a Unique Sample of Observations Lies between $-\infty$ and Any Given Distance of the Mean of the Population from Which the Sample Is Drawn." Biometrika 11(4): 414–417.

Student. 1909. "The Distribution of the Means of Samples Which Are Not Drawn at Random." Biometrika 7(1-2): 210–214.

Student. 1908. "Probable Error of a Correlation Coefficient." Biometrika 6(2-3): 302–310.

Student. 1908. "The Probable Error of a Mean." Biometrika 6(1): 1–25.

Student. 1907. "On the Error of Counting with a Haemacytometer." Biometrika 5(3): 351–360.

OTHER PUBLICATIONS

Student. 1905. "The Pearson Co-efficient of Correlation." Supplement to Report of 1904, Arthur Guinness Son & Company.

Student. 1904. "The Application of the 'Law of Error' to the Work of the Brewery." Report, Arthur Guinness Son & Company.

Funding

Grants

Africa Oxford Catalyst Grant (Co-I, coordinated the application)

£3500 [2024]

UKRI MRC PHIND Grant (Co-I, led the application)

£150,000 [2023-24]

£1,000 [2023] - SoGE Research Environment and Culture Fund (led)

£35,000 [2020-23] - ESRC IAA Grant Stages 1, 2, 3 (Co-I, co-wrote the applications)

£1,000 [2016] - SoGE Engagement and Impact Inspiration Fund Grant (led)

\$6,000 [2011] - Canada NSERC Undergraduate Research Grant (led)

Awards

 $\pounds 500~[2022]$ - SoGE ECR Engagement and Impact Award $\pounds 1000~[2011]$ - McGill University Davidovic Field Study Award

Scholarships

 $\pounds 100{,}000$ [2017-20] - Commonwealth Scholarship for Doctoral Study in the UK

 $\pounds 5{,}000$ [2015-16] - Linacre College Canadian National Scholarship

£5,000 [2015-16] - SoGE Departmental Scholarship